Were you successful? Let's try together now. We have one action creator already,
Baarl olduunuz yerde birlikte alarsanz, bir eylem Oluturucumuz zaten var.
now I'll add more.
imdi daha fazlasn ekleyeceim.
The second one I'll add is simply called decrement,
Ekleyeceim ikinciye sadece zarar verici denir.
therefore the type will be decrement,
Bu nedenle tr zarara urayacaktr.
I don't need to pass any payload to it. Now
u an iin herhangi bir yk tamama gerek yok.
come add and subtract
Gelin ve kn.
so let's start with add, I'll name the function add
yleyse en azndan adresindeki ilevle balayalm.
and here, we now need a payload.
te burda bir yk gerekiyor.
If we have a look at the counter.js file where we dispatch it, there
James Fowler'n sayacna bakyoruz, oraya gnderiyoruz.
we set up a payload value 10 or value 15,
Bir yk yk deeri 10 veya deer 15 ayarladk.
how do we get that payload into our action creator?
Bu yk eylem yaratcsna nasl ulatracaz.
Well keep in mind, we execute it here in our container
Burada, konteynrmzda idam ettiimizi unutmayn.
so this is where we probably want to pass any payload as arguments to the action creator,
Dolaysyla, muhtemelen gerek ykleyiciye argmanlar olarak herhangi bir yk iletmek istiyoruz.
so we should expect that payload as arguments.
Dolaysyla yk argmanlar olarak beklemeliyiz.
So here for example, a value argument you can name it whatever you like, to then set the val property
rnein, burada bir deer argman vererek istediiniz deeri verebilir, ardndan deer mlkn ayarlayabilirsiniz.
and I'll just use the value here because I use that before so that I don't have to change my code in the
gerekiyor, yalnzca o eylemi gelen deere eit olarak ayarlayabilirsiniz.
reducer so well on the created action where we set equal to the incoming value.
Ve haveli'yi burada kullanacam nk daha nce bunu kullandm, bylece redktrdeki kodumu deitirmem
Now the same will happen for subtract, oh I should also change the type before I do that though,
imdi ayn ey karmak iin de geerli olacak ya da bunu yapmaktan nce yazmaya balayacam.
so the same will now happen to subtract, there subtract like this type should be set to subtract
Bylece, imdi bu tr karlacak ekilde kartlacak ekilde kartlacaktr.
and I also get the value which I'll pass on on the val prop.
Ayrca deer pervanesine aktarlacam deeri de alyorlar.
Now finally, if we have a look at the counter.js file for the container, we also see for onStore and
Nihayetinde, konteyner iin Jarius tezgahna bakarsak, dkkn zerinde drt tane ve
onDeleteResults, so for the actions dispatched there,
orada gnderilen 40 eylemin sonucunu gryoruz.
we also get a payload result and resultElId, so we should also create the action creators with these
Ayrca bir yk tama sonucu elde ediyoruz ve kimlii zdk, bu yzden bu ykleri aklda tutarak da
payloads in mind.
eylem yaratclar oluturmamz gerekiyor.
So I'll just add another action, another action creator I should say, I'll name this one storeResult,
Bu yzden sadece Navier eylemi oluturan baka bir eylem ekleyeceim veya hepsini bir maaza sonucu olarak sylemeliyim.
that's the camel case notation I was referring to, starting with a lower case character but each word
Bu, deve kutusu notasyonunun kk harfli bir karaktere balamas gerektiidir, ancak st kelimenin
inside the entire word then starts with an upper case one.
iindeki her kelime daha sonra byk harf 1 ile balar.
So here in this action creator for the storeResult action, I will get my result
Dolaysyla burada maaza saldr eylemi iin bu eylem yaratan benim sonucumu alacam.
I want to store and I expect to have a result property on the action which gets created in the end.
Maazamda saklamak istiyorum ve sonuta yaratlan eylem konusunda zlm bir mlkm olmasn bekliyorum.
So let's go over there, let's expect the value or argument which I will name res, you can pick any name
yleyse oraya gidelim, beklediiniz deer veya argman, sizin isminiz varsa istediiniz
you want,
ismi seebileceiz.
important, a result property has to be set and I will pass res as a value, the type also is a different
sonu zellii ayarlanmal ve dinlenme deeri olarak gemelidir. D tipi balsamlar farkldr.
one,
nemli
it's storeResult.
Maazann sonucu.
Now finally, let's create the action created for the last action we have.
imdi nihayet sahip olduumuz son eylem iin oluturulan eylemi oluturalm.
It was deleteResult so I'll name it appropriately, here
nde gelen sonutur, bu yzden burada uygun ekilde adlandracam.
I get the result element ID and therefore the type will be deleteResult
zlen e kimliini alyorum ve bu nedenle tr sonu olacak.
and if we consult our counter container one more time, we see that previously we dispatched an action
Hesabmz veya konteyneri bir kez daha iptal edersek, daha nce tuz ncesi fikrin bir mlk olarak
with ResultElId as a property, we should keep that pattern so that our reducers still works
bulunduu bir eylem gnderdiimizi grrz ki, redktrlerin almaya devam etmesi iin bu rnty muhafaza etmeliyiz.
so let's copy that property name, head back to the actions file, set it as a property here and assign the
ve gelen geri kalan kimlik deerini bir deer olarak atadn syleyen eylemler listesine kopyalayalm.
incoming resElId value as a value.
yleyse, bu mlk adn, burada bir zellik bulunduunu
With that, we got a bunch of action creators,
Bununla bir sr aksiyon yaratcs var.
we can now import them all in our counter.js file.
Artk hepsini tezgahmzda alabiliriz sadece deriz.
So there I will simply import everything as action creators and now, I can use them down there when
Dolaysyla her eyi her eyi aksiyon yaratclar olarak ie aktaracam ve imdi onlara yamlandnda bunlar
I dispatch them.
orada kullanabiliriz.
So for example, increment now needs to be called on action creators, the same for decrement, you can use
Dolaysyla, rnein artmn imdi eylem yaratclar zerinde Decora iin ayn ekilde arlmas gerekiyor ve eylem
action creators and call decrement there,
yaratclarn kullanabilirsiniz ve orada azaltma denir.
the same of course for add, there we call the add method but here we need to pass the value as an argument
burada da add yntemi arlyor, ancak burada rendike deeri bir argman olarak vermemiz gerekiyor.
as you learned
Tabii ki
so make sure to do that. For delete, you can also call delete, excuse me, subtract and pass a value there
Bu nedenle silmek iin de yaptnzdan emin olun, ayn zamanda silebilirsiniz zr deyip karma ve oraya bir deer iletme de yapabilirsiniz.
so there we used, if I have a look at the caption, 15
Bu yzden balk 15'e bir gz atardk.
so let me subtract 15 here.
Brak 15 burada karmama izin ver.
And for the storeResult action, I'll call action creators store result, here we need to pass the result
Ve maaza saldr eylemi iin koleksiyon yaratclarmz saldrlar saklamlar burada saldrya gemeliyiz.
we want to store and we receive this here as an argument to that property related method,
Siz saklamak istiyor ve biz bunu bu mlkle ilgili yntemin bir argman olarak aldk.
so here I will pass on result.
Bylece burada sonu vereceim.
And finally, for delete result, I'll call action creators delete result and pass my ID on, the ID is
ection yaratclarn deleter saldrya aracam ve kimliimi kimliime geirip hepsini bu isimsiz ilevle alyorum.
also received on this anonymous function.
Ve nihayet deleter saldrlar iin
So I'm just using the action creators here to create actions,
Dolaysyla, yalnzca gerek yaratclar eylemler oluturmak iin kullanyorum.
I still dispatch the same actions as before,
Hala daha nce olduu gibi ayn eylemleri gnderdim.
this didn't change. Now I still get an error that some file isn't found,
Bu deimedi, halen hl baz faul bulunmayan bir hata buluyorum.
this should be a bug here,
Buraya dnm olmal.
I'll simply restart npm start and it should fix it,
NPM balang ilemini yeniden balatacam ve dzeltmesi gerekecek.
let's see, yeah
Hadi grelim evet.
it was pointing at the wrong file but we still have a problem in the reducer
Yanl dosyaya iaret ediyordu, ancak redktrde hala bir sorunumuz var.
which makes sense because we moved the position of the actions.js file.
Bu, mantkl nk son bir sonbaharda projenin yerini deitirdik.
So in our reducers, we have to adjust the import paths, it's no longer in the folder above the reducers
Dolaysyla redktrmzde artk redktr klasrnn stndeki klasre ait olmayan ithalat paundlarn ayarlamamz
folder,
gerekiyor.
there we have to go into the actions folder instead and then it will work again.
Orada eylem klasrne gitmeliyiz ve sonra tekrar alacak.
So adjust the import paths in both reducers like this,
Bu yzden her iki redktrde de pauvres ithal ediyorum.
save everything and thereafter the application should work again.
Her eyi kaydedin ve bundan sonra uygulama tekrar almaldr.
So now I click these buttons and we see indeed that we are successfully manipulating our store again, this time
imdi bu dmeleri tklayn ve aslnda, bu sefer eylem yaratclarmz araclyla maazamz baarl bir ekilde idare
through our action creators though. Thus far, only synchronous code runs in them,
ettiimizi gryoruz, ancak bugne kadar yalnzca senkron kod alyor.
as I said action creators are useful for handling asynchronous code
Dediim gibi ection yaratclar asenkron kodu ilemek iin kullanldr.
so let's dive into asynchronous code next.
Sradaki zaman uyumsuz koda geelim.
But let me also quickly elaborate on the question whether we should use them for synchronous code or not,
Ancak bunlar Circulus kodu iin kullanp kullanmamamz gerektiini de hzl bir ekilde ele alalm.
the answer is it's up to you,
Cevap, size kalm olmasdr.
it's a clean way of creating your actions,
Bu, eylemlerinizi yaratmann temiz bir yoludur.
you have everything about actions in one file,
lemlerle ilgili her eye bir dosyada sahipsiniz.
you don't have to create the action objects anywhere else.
Eylem nesnelerini baka hibir yerde yaratmanz gerekmez.
This is a tiny cleanup which can be considered good so nothing speaks against using action creators
bir temizliktir, bylece hibir ey gerek yaratclar senkron kod iin ok kullanmaya kar konumaz.
for synchronous code too
Bu, iyi dnlm kk
but as I said, it will be extremely useful for asynchronous code.
Ancak dediim gibi asenkron kod iin son derece yararl olacaktr.
We'll see this in the next lecture.
Bunu bir sonraki dersimizde greceiz.